Federico Rubino

Software Engineer

Personal Info

Email

federico.rubino8@gmail.com

Phone

8315887750

GitHub

https://github.com/FedericoRubino

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/federico-rubino-4b7132184/

Skills

Java

Python

Machine learning

Android studio

C++

Pandas

Javascript

Html

Keras

Leadership

Communication

Teamwork

Time management

Problem solving

Languages

German

English

Italian

I am calm and collected during any situation and have shown strong leadership skills throughout my work and social life. I have experience in teaching all aspects of science to students K-12 and above, as well as tutoring in Java, Python and design patters. I have shown on multiple occasions that I am great at resolving conflict and that I can adapt to learn in many work environments. I am also charismatic and kind when working with coworkers and customers.

Education

2019-09

California State University Monterey Bay, Seaside

- present

Bachelor in Computer Science, Data Science/ Software Engineering

2015-01

Cabrillo College, Aptos

- 2019-05

Associates in Engineering, Engineering/ Computer Science

Work History

2020-01

Teaching Assistant/ TA coordinator

- present

CSUMB, Seaside

- Proved mastery of different computer science skills on a regular basis
- · Resolved all issues professionally and in a timely manner
- Utilized strong interpersonal and communications skills to serve fellow students

2019-06

QE Database Admin Intern

- 2019-12

Poly/ Plantronics Inc., Santa Cruz

- Cleaned, managed, and automated the processing of their legacy documents
- Used Python and Java to automate the proper documentation of thousands of documents while working with different technical tools
- Lead meetings, maintained high collegiality among professionals, and regularly presented in front of a global team

2018-12

Afterschool Science Teacher

- 2019-06

Environmental Science Workshop Watsonville

- Mentored and taught elementary school students different sciences such as biology, chemistry, and physics
- On a daily basis, I proved that I have a strong understanding of the sciences and the ability to convey knowledge through projects and simple lectures
- Worked collaboratively in a team environment

Projects

2020-08

EEG Research Neural Net Project

- present

Using machine learning and neural net techniques my team and I get to utilize Python, Pandas, and Keras to develop a system that can use EEG data to make predictions. We are currently in the process of publishing a paper regarding this project.

2020-09

ReMi Meditation Android App

present

Designed, developed and deployed a professional looking android app with a custum interfaces and databases for a group project.